Stephen Godfrey

Palo Alto, CA / 650-475-6159 / stephengodfrey223@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Analytical thinker and strategic planner with a proven track record of driving new initiatives to successful completions and through a unique combination of managerial experience, quantitative skills and passion, helping firms design strategies, build products and deliver results

KEY SKILLS

- Product definition and road mapping
- Initiative management
- Quantitative analysis
- Statistical regression and classification modeling
- Machine learning techniques
- Natural language processing
- Data visualization
- Python, SQL, Visual Basic

EDUCATION

General Assembly Data Science Immersive May 2019

University of California, Los Angeles – The Anderson School MBA, 1993

University of California, Los Angeles

BS Applied Mathematics/ Economics, 1989

VOLUNTEER

Member UCLA Math and Stats Chair's Council

Member Board of Trustees of First Congregational Church of Palo Alto

CAREER ACHIEVEMENTS

eCommerce leadership led Foreign Exchange (FX) eCommerce teams for two major banks providing client-facing user-interface and API tools and each generating over \$350MM in annual revenue

New product delivery responsible for the successful launch of new products including an API suite, an online portal and online trading applications

Quantitative analysis demonstrated expertise in applying quantitative techniques including building a financial risk research service, authoring papers and pursuing a data science immersive program

Broad management led product management, sales, service, trading and research teams of over 50 members

WORK EXPERIENCE

Wells Fargo Bank Head of FX eCommerce, San Francisco • 2010 to 2018 • Led product management, domain sales and service for the \$350MM-revenue electronic FX revenue division • Delivered user interface and API products to clients • Prioritized, funded and executed the eFX product roadmap • Spearheaded major infrastructure and compliance buildouts

Bank of America Merrill Lynch Co-head of FX eSolutions, San Francisco, London, Los Angeles • 1992 to 2010

 Co-led the global electronic trading, cross-currency payment and consumer FX teams generating \$400MM in annual revenue • Sold hedging solutions to multinational corporations • Spearheaded launch of the GCIB portal • Co-created a risk-assessment research group to work with clients and publish research

Sanwa Trust Bank Equity Analyst, Los Angeles • 1992

Built quantitative models for equity valuation and portfolio selection

TSA Capital Management Quant Analyst, Los Angeles • 1989 to 1992

Built statistical asset allocation models